A Guide to the William Faulkner Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10186
William Faulkner Collection 1935-1960
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10186
12 items
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions on access to the Library's microfilms of the William Faulkner manuscripts in its custody; the microfilm may be consulted by any interested party, and it will be lent through the interlibrary loan system. Materials are constantly added. Long-term loans may be arranged. Use of the microfilm will be restricted to the premises of the borrowing library. No loans will be made to individuals. Researchers should enquire of the Manuscripts Division concerning availability of microfilm of manuscripts that are pertinent to their work. Most of the literary manuscripts in our collections written by Faulkner, both holograph and typescript, have also been published in facsimile in William Faulkner Manuscripts, 25 vols (New York: Garland, 1986-87).
By the terms of the agreement by which the William Faulkner Foundation transferred the original manuscripts to the University, access to the original manuscripts is restricted (to ensure the survival of the physically-delicate originals) to doctoral candidates at the dissertation stage of their programs, and to certain mature scholars and critics. But even these researchers must demonstrate need to see the originals that goes beyond the requirements of most routine research. A doctoral candidate at the dissertation stage, or other qualified researcher who believes that his or her work requires access to the originals must correspond with the Curator of Manuscripts prior to arrival at the Library to obtain permission for access.
No microfilm, electrostatic, or other types of copies may be made of materials written by William Faulkner that are in our William Faulkner Collections. Other materials in the collections may be copied subject to the normal rules of the Library established under the conditions of the Copyright Act. All copying is performed by the Printing Services Department of the University.
Acquisition Information
These screenplays were a gift from the Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation, Beverly Hills, California 14 December 1976.
WILLIAM FAULKNER COLLECTION
- Item Listing
  - Road to Glory (Wooden Crosses) -filmscript worked on by William Faulkner, 1935 Dec 31; TMs electrostatic copy 172 p. (Box Box 1)
  - Road to Glory (Wooden Crosses) -later filmscript, 1936 Jan 14; TMs electrostatic copy 129 p. (Box Box 1)
  - Road to Glory (Zero Hour) -"final" filmscript, 1936 Jan 27; TMs electrostatic copy 144 p. (Box Box 1)
  - Banjo on My Knee -"treatment" for filmscript by William Faulkner, 1936 Mar 3 & 10(?); TMs electrostatic copy 50 p. (Box Box 1)
  - Banjo on My Knee -"revised treatment" by William Faulkner, 1936 Mar 10; TMs electrostatic copy 37 p. (Box Box 1)
  - Slave Ship (The Last Slaver) -"revised final" script, 1936 Sep 24; TMs electrostatic copy 157 p. (Box Box 1)
  - Splinter Fleet (Submarine Patrol) -early filmscript, 1936 Dec 7; TMs electrostatic copy 131 p. (Box Box 2)
  - Submarine Patrol (Splinter Fleet) -"first draft community", 1936 Dec 22; TMs electrostatic copy 133 p. (Box Box 2)
  - Drums Along the Mohawk -"treatment" by William Faulkner, 193? Mar 15; TMs electrostatic copy 29 p. (Box Box 2)
  - The Long Hot Summer -"final" filmscript by Irving Ravetch and Harriet Frank, Jr. adapted from short stories by William Faulkner, 1957 Aug 26; TMs electrostatic copy 152 p. (Box Box 2)
  - The Sound and the Fury -filmscript by Irving Ravetch and Harriet Frank, Jr. adapted from William Faulkner's novel, 1958 Jul 1; TMs electrostatic copy 138 p. (Box Box 2)
  - Sanctuary -"final" filmscript written by James Poe, adapted from the novel by William Faulkner, 1960 Jul 15; TMs electrostatic copy (Box Box 2)